const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is the FIRST step in the Waterfall process?",
    options: [
      "a. Implementation",
      "b. Integration Testing",
      "c. Requirements Definition",
      "d. Maintenance",
    ],
    answer: "c. Requirements Definition",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT part of the Agile Manifesto?",
    options: [
      "a. Individuals and interactions over processes and tools",
      "b. Working software over comprehensive documentation",
      "c. Customer collaboration over contract negotiation",
      "d. Following a plan above all else",
    ],
    answer: "d. Following a plan above all else",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a Scrum event?",
    options: ["a. Sprint Planning", "b. Daily Standup", "c. Sprint Review", "d. Pair-programming"],
    answer: "d. Pair-programming",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What is TRUE about story points?",
    options: [
      "a. Estimates for story points are always accurate",
      "b. The raw value is unimportant compared to the relative value",
      "c. The number of story points represents only the difficulty of a story",
      "d. Story points are part of the Waterfall process",
    ],
    answer: "b. The raw value is unimportant compared to the relative value",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "Which of the following is a DevOps practice?",
    options: [
      "a. Automating everything",
      "b. Enforcing the deployment process",
      "c. Developing infrastructure code with the same practices as application code",
      "d. All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "d. All of the above",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "Which of the following is a pitfall to avoid when writing requirements?",
    options: [
      "a. Wishful thinking",
      "b. Complete sentences",
      "c. Plain language",
      "d. Testability",
    ],
    answer: "a. Wishful thinking",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is true about scheduling?",
    options: [
      "a. It is easy to estimate the difficulty of problems when scheduling",
      "b. Productivity is directly proportional to the amount of people working on a task",
      "c. Adding people to a 'late' project can cause communication overheads",
      "d. Planning for contingencies is not needed",
    ],
    answer: "c. Adding people to a 'late' project can cause communication overheads",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "What does PERT stand for?",
    options: [
      "a. Program Evaluation and Review Technique",
      "b. Programming Environment and React Technology",
      "c. Purple Elephants Riding Tricycles",
      "d. PHP Executes Recursive Tasks",
    ],
    answer: "a. Program Evaluation and Review Technique",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "Which of the following is a project effort estimation technique that primarily relies on mathematical formulas?",
    options: [
      "a. Experience based techniques",
      "b. Algorithmic cost modeling",
      "c. Expert judgement",
      "d. Just ballparking an estimate",
    ],
    answer: "b. Algorithmic cost modeling",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT an architectural pattern?",
    options: [
      "a. Model View Controller Architecture",
      "b. Layered Architecture",
      "c. Building Architecture",
      "d. Pipe-and-filter Architecture",
    ],
    answer: "c. Building Architecture",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "What is generalization in UML class diagrams?",
    options: [
      "a. Inheritance hierarchies between classes",
      "b. 'Has a' relationships between classes",
      "c. Attribute types",
      "d. The programming language used in the diagram",
    ],
    answer: "a. Inheritance hierarchies between classes",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question:
      "Which design pattern is used when multiple presentations of an objectâ€™s state are needed?",
    options: [
      "a. Shapeshifter pattern",
      "b. Meta pattern",
      "c. Observer pattern",
      "d. None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "c. Observer pattern",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "Which of the following measures code understandability?",
    options: [
      "a. Big-O notation",
      "b. Story points",
      "c. Amount of unit tests",
      "d. None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "d. None of the above",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question:
      "What is the type of testing that tests smaller, isolated blocks of application code?",
    options: [
      "a. Integration testing",
      "b. Automation testing",
      "c. Unit testing",
      "d. Code review",
    ],
    answer: "c. Unit testing",
  },
];

export default questions;
